

## Contact





Dolziger Str. 3 10247 Berlin, Germany

Linkedin Profile

# Skills

- Python
- SQL
- Classical Machine Learning Models
- Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- Explainable AI (XAI)
- PyTorch
- AI/ML Pipelines
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- Terraform
- GitHub Actions
- ReactJS
- Flask APIs
- TensorFlow
- scikit-learn
- Scrum
- JIRA
- Microsoft Office
- Problem-solving

**Teamwork** 

# Languages

English- Professional Working

Proficiency (C1)

Deutsch - Full professional

fluency (B1/B2)

# Hobbies:

Song Writing, Graphic Design, Video Making

# Xhemal Kodragjini

## Summary

Software Engineer with an experience of 4 years between ML, project management and Cloud. Demonstrated ability to design and implement end-toend solutions, in both technical and management scope. Currently pursuing a Master in Data Science at Freie Universität Berlin. Seeking roles in Machine Learning Engineering, or Data Science to further advance my knowledge.

## Work Experience

#### CLOUD PLATFORM ENGINEER

July 2023 - December 2024

Deutsche Bank - Berlin

- Deployed GCP resources and services (e.g., Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), IAM bindings, Cloud SQL instance) through Terraform using Infrastructure as Code principle (IaC)
- Updated GitHub Actions workflows to perform new actions within the Google Cloud infrastructure of the Bank
- Wrote Python scripts to change the version of requested Terraform workspaces and create new Azure Active Directory groups using Terraform API
- · Supported in developing a Terraform module

#### **GRADUATE IT TRAINEE**

October 2021 - March 2023

Deutsche Börse AG - Frankfurt am Main

- Collected business requirements and delivered the Proof of Concept (PoC) for an OCR (Optical character recognition) project in Product Development Lab.
- Delivered project execution guidelines to be used within Corporate IT department.
- Supported on the creation of the RunBook for an internal program, collecting technical tasks and analysing dependencies between systems.
- Delivered workshops and demo sessions on the usage of DocuSign functionalities.

#### AI SOFTWARE ENGINEER

IQ Wireless GmbH - Berlin

April 2021 - September 2021

- Developed a web application to fully automate the AI pipeline, including parameter selection, real-time training and testing progress of fire detection, and visualizations.
- Used Flask(backend), React JS (frontend), Jenkins (automation), Python (scripting).
- Planned and implemented the project, prepared the infrastructure/environment, developed the UI and APIs for the data exchange.

## MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

October 2020 - March 2021

IQ Wireless GmbH - Berlin

- Supported on training and testing Faster R-CNN for fire detection in image sets
- Created and balanced training/testing sets
- Performed visualization using Pandas, NumPy, Dash, Plotly to get insights on data
- Wrote Python scripts to automate different processes within the Al workflow

## Education

## MASTER

Data Science

2023 - Ongoing

Freie Universität Berlin - Berlin

Relevant Courses: Statistics for DS, Machine Learning, Seminar in Explainable AI, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning in Bioinformatics, Machine Learning Project

Other: Deutschland Stipendium 2023, 2024 Holder

**BACHELOR** 2017 - 2021

Computer Engineering and Information Technology Canadian Institute of Technology - Tirana, Albania

Relevant Courses: Database Systems, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Operating Systems, Computer Science Fundamentals

Thesis: "Predicting Autism Spectrum Disorder with ML Classification Algorithms" Other: Awarded a full scholarship for 3 years, Final GPA: 3.99 out of 4.0, CEEPUS Exchange student at University of Maribor, Slovenia (March 2020 - June 2020)